Hello Everyone, taking out health insurance is
not an easy decision.   There
are many options in the market, but
clarity is needed to choose a plan
.  In this video, we will review the AG
Medicare Select policy in detail
.  Let's look at the advantages,
disadvantages, policy features, and
limitations one by one
.  I am Ajith from Dito
Insurance.  Our goal is to help you choose the best policy for you
.  So
watch the video till the end, it will be useful for you
.  If you want free guidance,
the link is in the description. Book a free call
.  Our insurance
advisors will help you with your insurance decision
.  So let's start with
the policy. First, let's look at the company's background.
First, a short introduction. Tata
AG is a brand that is known to almost everyone
.  Started in 2001, it is a
wide-ranging company with 11,000 plus network hospitals.  So
if we look at the claim settlement ratio, it is 96%, which means that out of
every 100 claims, 96
claims are being settled.
If you look at the complaints ratio, it is low,
only 11 complaints per 10,000
claims, so overall the insurance
company's metrics are reliable.
And coming to the policy, Medicare Select
covers all the basic features
.  So we are being provided with sum insured ranging
from 5 lakhs to 3 crores
.  And waiting periods are
usual, so during the initial 30-day waiting
period, we are only
covered for accidents.  And two years of
specific ills waiting period.  So,
we do not provide coverage for some conditions like
kidney stones, cataracts, and other slow-
growing conditions
.  And there is also a three-year pre-
existing disease waiting period
.  If we have
any pre-existing conditions before taking out a policy,
we will have to wait up to three years
.  But in this policy, we do
not have any rider that reduces the waiting period for pre-existing diseases.  So if we have pre-
existing conditions, we will have to serve this three-
year waiting period
.  And among the basic features,
we are providing inpatient hospitalization coverage up to a
certain limit
.  And pre- and post-
hospitalization coverage is 90 days and 90
days, meaning 90 days of expenses before admission
and
90 days of expenses after discharge are covered
.  And along with that, they are
also providing us with domiciliary coverage
.  And organ donor AYUSH
benefits and ambulance coverage are
provided up to the sum insured. In
addition to these basic features, we also have some highlight features in this policy
.  So the first thing is
restoration infinity plus so if we have to make
a claim after taking the policy, it will be
restored to us immediately after the claim settlement.  This means that if I
take out a 10-locks policy now,
my coverage will be refilled after every claim
.  That will be unlimited times
.  And there is a room rent restriction,
but it is category wise.  So, they will
accommodate us up to a single private room.  But if you are
admitted in twin sharing or multi sharing, you will
be given a daily cash benefit.  So, if you are admitted in twin sharing, you are provided with coverage of
up to ₹1200 per day and if you are
admitted in multi sharing, you are
provided with coverage of up to ₹1500 per day
.  So think of it as a bonus on top of the hospital bill
.  So, if I don't make an
insurance claim after taking out insurance, they are
providing me with a bonus
.  So, they are providing a 50% bonus
annually up to 100%, and
apart from this, they are also providing another option,
which is a
1% discount on the renewal premium, so you can choose either of them
.  If you want a bonus, they will provide you with a 50% up
to 100% or 1% discount on the renewal premium
.
We are
also providing some add-ons to customize this policy
.  First One Consumables
Benefit.  So we have been provided with coverage by default for things like gloves, syringes, and
PPE kits
.  But if we take this add-
on, coverage will be extended to them as well
.  Second One
Maternity Cover.  So anyone who wants delivery
charges covered
can take this add-on.  We are provided with 10% of the
sum insured up to a
maximum of Rs. 1,00,000 and to avail this benefit, we are
imposed with a waiting period of two years and
if you take the YD-ON,
we can further reduce this waiting period
to one year and another benefit is
infinite advantage for us. So with this YD-ON, we get
unlimited claim once in our lifetime,
that is, the insurance company will bear any bill without working with our sum insured
.  Another rider is Early
Access, which means that if you pay premiums for the next two
or three years at once, the
sum assured you receive in the next three years is
provided from the first year.  So
if I take a 10 lock cover and take this add-on, the
10 locks due in the next three years plus the 10 locks, a total of
30 locks, will be available to me from day one
.  And as per
the policy,
there is a room rent restriction after selecting the room category.  We
can only choose a single private room.
With this add-on, we are
also providing the chance to opt for a sweet room, deluxe room, etc. if we want.
And aggregate deductibles ranging
from 10,000 to 100,000, if we
select this deductible, we will be
given discounts on premiums.  So the final thoughts are that
Medicare Select offers flexibility
and provides you with high protection
and also offers one of the best
customization options.
So this policy is ideal for young families
and first-time buyers, and if you
also want a maternity benefit,
you can also consider this policy.
But remember, this is not a one-size-fits-all
plan.  So if you
want the perfect plan for your needs, book a free call
with Dito. The link is in the
description. If you want to
see more reviews like this, please subscribe
to Dito Insurance Telugu. I am Ajith.
Signing of Stay Healthy Stay Insured.